Welcome to our training "Manage Your Experiments" - plan a test of your listing content.
Brands enrolled in Amazon Brand Registry enjoy greater control over their product detail pages,
but it can still be challenging to decide which listing content will drive the most sales.
That's why we created the "Manage Your Experiments" tool, or M-Y-E.
M-Y-E lets brands compare components of their current detail page content with an alternate version
to see which performs better.
You can test two main images, product titles, product descriptions, or sets of "About This Item"
bullets,
or you can test two versions of an A+ content product description.
In this first video of the "Manage Your Experiments" series, we'll show you how to plan an M-Y-E
test.
You can also learn how to set up a test in the M-Y-E tool and how to interpret the results of an
experiment
by watching the second and third videos in this series.
Before we review the steps for planning an M-Y-E test,
it's important to note that a product needs to belong to a brand enrolled in Brand Registry to be
part of an experiment.
The seller setting up the experiment in M-Y-E also needs to be internal to the brand.
If you'd like more information about Brand Registry and access to brand selling benefits like M-
Y-E,
see the series of modules in our Seller University course,
launch your brand in the Amazon store.
You should start planning your M-Y-E experiment by identifying the ASINs associated with the detail
page content you want to test.
We recommend going into the M-Y-E tool to double-check that those ASINs are eligible for testing.
Hover over Brands in the main menu in Seller Central.
Click Build Your Brand, then click Manage Your Experiments in the list of supporting programs.
On the next page, click the Get Started with Manage Your Experiments button to go to the tool.
Then click the Create a New Experiment drop-down menu and select the type of listing content you're
planning to test.
If you select bullet points, main image, product description, or product title, a pop-up containing
reference ASINs will appear.
If you select A+ content, you'll be taken to the A+ content manager where you can click the Select
a Reference ASIN button to open a similar pop-up.
Products are displayed as reference ASINs in either pop-up when they've had enough detail page traffic
in recent weeks to support reliable M-Y-E testing.
The exact amount of traffic needed varies by product category.
It may require several dozen orders per week or more.
Each of the reference ASINs displayed for M-Y-E will also have an eligibility status listed.
If an ASIN is currently ineligible for M-Y-E testing, you'll see a reason and may be able to make
adjustments so the ASIN becomes eligible.
As you review eligible reference ASINs, keep in mind that for title and image experiments, you can
test multiple products within a variation family.
When you select an ASIN that's part of a variation family during setup, M-Y-E will populate both
the parent and child products.
You'll be able to deselect individual child products, but the parent product must be part of your
M-Y-E test because it's the primary driver of detail page traffic.
If you're planning to test A+ content with M-Y-E, keep in mind that we'll cascade your experiment
across all products that have your existing content published on their detail pages.
After you select the A+ content you want to test during setup, you'll be able to see all associated
ASINs, including variations.
But you won't be able to deselect associated ASINs.
That's to prevent mismatched A+ content from appearing to customers.
While identifying ASINs for your experiment, it's also important to remember that you can only run
one M-Y-E test at a time on a product.
If you're testing two different titles, you can't also test two images for the same ASIN, but you
can run multiple M-Y-E tests for different ASINs at the same time.
And we recommend running multiple tests on the same ASIN one after the other to help refine results
and increase the impact of testing.
After identifying ASINs for your M-Y-E test, the next step is defining a hypothesis.
We recommend writing it down and collecting feedback so you can be sure your hypothesis is specific
and based on a well-defined assumption.
For example, your hypothesis might be adding descriptive detail to my product title will increase
the number of customers who make a purchase, or replacing A+ content product images with an infographic
will increase the number of units sold.
As the final piece of planning for your M-Y-E experiment, you'll design your alternate content.
Draft your title about this item bullets or product description.
Create a new main image or collect everything you'll need for new A+ content.
Doing this work now can help prevent errors during setup for your test, and it will allow you to
build your experiment in M-Y-E more quickly.
While designing your alternate content, we recommend reviewing relevant requirements and guidelines
on Seller Central Help pages.
You should also keep in mind that successful experiments usually test content very different from
what's already published in the Amazon Store.
Test a 50-character product title against a 200-character title, for example, or test static A+
content images of your products against images that show them in motion.
This concludes our training on planning an M-Y-E test.
We encourage you to watch the next video in our series, which provides step-by-step instructions
for setting up an M-Y-E experiment.
Thank you, and happy selling in the Amazon Store!